Guide to the Lloyd R. Fortney Papers, 1964-1998
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Lloyd R. Fortney papers 1964-1998
University Archives, Duke University
Fortney, Lloyd R.
2.5 Linear Feet 1,000 Items
Lloyd Fortney was a professor of Physics at Duke University.
His collection includes grant proposals, correspondence, memos and documents relating to the Physics Department and the Graduate School.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Lloyd R. Fortney Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1998.
Biographical Note
Lloyd Fortney was born in Enid, Oklahoma in 1936. He received his B.S. from New Mexico State University in 1958, and his Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1962. He came to Duke in 1963 as a research associate; he became a professor in the Physics Department starting in 1964 and remained for the next 35 years. His primary field of research included high energy physics, instrumentation and date acquisition, microelectronics applications, and software development. He taught courses in technical physics, mechanics, particle physics, electronic, and computer applications to measurement. He died in March 1999.
Collection Overview
Contains grant proposals, department and Graduate School correspondence, memos and financial documents from the years roughly 1964-98.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Dept. of Physics
Duke University -- Faculty.
Related Material
Gordy (Walter) Papers, 1949-1986.
University Archives. Duke University.
London (Fritz) Papers, 1922-1994 (bulk 1926-1954).
University Archives. Duke University.
Meier (Otto) Records and Papers, 1931-1979.
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Atomic Energy Commission Proposals, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Energy Research and Development Administration Proposals, 1976-1977
  - Atomic Energy Commission Proposal, 1978
  - Department of Energy Proposal, 1979-1988
  - Correspondence
  - National Science Foundation Proposal, 1968-1976
  - Bubble Chamber Proposals, 1976-1984
  - Financial Correspondence
  - Financial Statements
  - Graduate School and Department Memos, 1987-1988
  - Department of Energy Proposals, 1988-1990
  - Financial Documents and Memos, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
  - Department of Energy Proposals, 1990-1994
  - Physics Department Memos and Documents, 1990-1991